Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a dynamic helper for player character to
get started.
If we head over to the images folder and then briefly close on our engine and attached in the lecture
of this course, I'm going to make sure to include these two images, just select them and then drag
them into Unreal Engine.
Once you've done that to make the images clear so that both of them and then right click scratchings
and apply paper to the texture settings.
So we're going to create a dynamic health bar.
So if I play a character has five pieces of health, then we're going to share five parts on our screen.
So in order to create the system, we'll create two widget blueprints.
The first one is just going to be of the heart.
So if we right click and go user interface as that widget blueprint.
I just call this hot.
Underscore budget blueprint.
Then if we head inside here.
The go to palette and look for canvas panel and just drag this into our designer.
Then we will look for an image.
And under the brush.
We just want to look for the heart full image that we just imported and adjust its size.
So it looks kind of normal.
Not to happy with it.
Just move it to the top left corner and under details.
Just give this name of hot.
Oh.
Then I need you to just right click and duplicate this image.
So make sure it's in the exact same position.
So my first heart is in position 12 position Y.
So I'm just going to make sure the second heart is in the exact same position.
12.
24.
Ben with the second image.
Select the heart empty.
Then just cool this image.
Heart.
Empty.
And under the Z order, make it minus one.
So whatever has the highest order will be turned on top.
So the idea here is when I play a character, has a piece of health that will be represented by this
heart.
However, if I play a character loses one of their health, then the heart will hide and we'll show
this heart empty image so that it's clear to the player that they've lost a piece of health.
So just turn this on and make sure that the heart fall is on top of the heart empty image.
Once you've done that, you can just click, compile and save and then close this.
Next, we will create another widget, which is going to be our player's HUD.
So if we just right click and go user interface.
So Widget Blueprint cast and this time call it Player HUD underscore Widget Blueprint.
If we open up our player hard, we're going to make this hard.
Show them out that my player character has in the palette.
If we look for a canvas panel and just drag it in, then I want you to look for a wrap box and just
drag it in and make it look something like mine.
So the idea here is early on we made this hot and one hot represents one piece of health.
So in our player hot, if our player character has five pieces of health, then we're going to spawn
five hearts inside of this wrap box.
But first, we need to give our player character some health.
So if I just close this and give it to my player character.
In the bare bones tab.
Let's create a new variable and call it health.
We'll make this variable type float and in the value we want it to be three.
So this will mean my character starts the game off with three pieces of health.
Just go compile and we go back to our player because we gave our player character three pieces of health.
That means when we start the game, I want this wrap box to spawn in three Hots, which will represent
my play characters, three pieces of health.
So in order to do that, we can head over to the graph and right click and look for event construct
and the bean construct which will fire.
As soon as this heart is spawned on our screen, we're going to get reference to my player character.
So to do that, if we right click and look, we'll get player character.
And from here, if we drag off for cost to play a beep or whatever your character is called.
And just hook us up here.
I'm going to right click on this and promote it to travel in case we need to reference this later.
Then we'll get the help that my player has.
So if you look at health, then we just want to drag up this value and look for true indicates.
So this trinket will convert this blue marble into an integer variable.
And the reason we're doing this is the next node that we're going to be using only works with integers.
So we need to convert our health variable.
After this, we'll just right click and look for for loop.
And so like this one, and pick up this return value until the last index.
So the way this four loop note will work is it will fire how many times my last index is.
So if my last index is five, then this four loop node is going to fire five times.
However, on the first index we just need to put a value of one because if I leave this at zero and
let's say my player character has five pieces of health because this for loop will start zero, this
will actually fire six times.
So for that reason, we need to make sure that our four loop starts at a value of one so that our four
loop will actually be accurate.
Next, we can hook this up.
Then?
Well, how many help my poor character has?
We're going to spawn in this hot widget blueprint.
Into our right box.
So on the right box, just cool this hot box.
And make sure it is available.
Then off of our phone, you just drag off and we'll create widget.
And under the widget course.
Let the.
Then want to drag in a hot box and a hot box and just drag up here and look for add child to wrap box
and hook up the return value into here.
And this and here.
And this will create a hardware blueprint and then add it to our hot box later on in our game.
We're going to be making a demo system.
And when we make a demo system, we're going to hide our hearts.
So we need to create a reference to each of our hearts.
In order to do that, we're going to create an array.
So if we create a new variable and just call this hot reference.
And inside of this heart reference, we're going to keep a reference of each heart that we spawn.
So under variable type, look for heart widget, blueprint and set object reference.
Then under here, just like this to be array.
So an array can hold multiple variables.
If I just go compile and go down and just add a bunch of elements.
My array can hold multiple values.
So that's why we're making an array.
After we sworn in, our heart was driven in order to create a reference of it.
We're going to drag in our heart reference variable and just drag or add.
And just connect the return value into here and listen to here.
And this will keep a reference of the heart that we want inside of this array.
And then we can just hook this up here.
Next, if we head back to our player, BP.
And some free space.
If we just right click and look for event, we can play, event we can play.
We're going to create a widget.
And that which is going to be our player hot.
We're going to reference this HUD later on.
So on the return body promote this to available and call this third reference.
Then after we've done this, we want to add this to our viewport.
So look for add to viewport.
Then we can go compile.
And now if I go play, I should spawn in the game with three hearts.
So I spend in the game and I have three hearts.
If you want to change the distance between each heart, what we can do is go back to our player heart.
And by I set the rap box in the search for padding.
And I can change the padding in the x and y value of something like 200.
Then each heart is going to be 200 units away from each other.
So I go compile and go play All my heart.
I've spaced away.
So I just thought I'd tell you that in case you wanted to do that.
But I'm going to leave mine at zero.
Another compile play by play character has three hots.
If I was to change my player's health to be something like.
For.
Then I'm going spoon in the game with four hearts.
Nice with that.
We have our health bar set up.